All right, this is fantastic. At this point, you should be set up with Visual Studio Code no Jas and get.
太好了，真是太棒了。现在，你应该已经配置好了 Visual Studio Code, node.js 以及 Git。
And I'm going to be working out of a folder called Hard Hat Free Code Camp
并且我将在一个名为 Hard Hat Free Code Camp(hh-fcc) 的文件夹下进行工作
at this point, you should have
现在，你应该已经有了
node, dash dash version, get dash dash
node --version 以及 git --version
And if you're using Windows,
如果你使用的是 Windows
this should say WsL or your boon to or something like that.
这里应该显示 WSL 或者 Ubuntu 或者其他类似的东西
And if you have all that, that means we're ready to go.
如果这些你都有了，那就表示我们已经准备好了
Now a quick note something that you'll see me do a lot. And you can do this as well.
现在我会对我经常做的一些操作做一个快速的解释，你也可以这样做
Oftentimes, when my terminal gets really, really big, or there's a ton of commands in here
通常，当我的终端变得非常非常大，或者是有成吨的命令放在这里时
gets a little bit overwhelming for me.
会让我感到有些困扰
So one thing that you can do is you can type clear, and hit Enter to clear it.
你可以做的一个操作是输入 "clear"，并按回车以清除它们
Or what you can do is you can hit Command K, if you're on a Mac,
你也可以按 "Command + k"，如果你是在 Mac 上
or Ctrl K, if you're on a Linux or a Windows,
或者是 "Ctrl + k"，如果你是在 Linux 或 Windows 上
and it's one of my favorite keyboard shortcuts that I use all the time.
这是我最喜欢的快捷键之一，我经常会使用它
Additionally, the trash can and the X here are very different.
另外，这里的终止键和X键是非常不同的
If I go to a couple of enters here, and we're down here,
比如说我在这里按几次回车，我们现在处于这个位置
if I hit the trashcan, and then pull my terminal back up,
如果我点击关闭，然后再把我的终端打开
by doing the toggle, or by doing terminal new terminal,
通过切换，或是通过“终端-新建终端”
you'll see all those lines are still here.
你可以看到这些行仍然还在这里
But if I hit the trashcan, and then pull the terminal back up,
但如果我点击终止按钮，再把终端打开回来
you'll see it actually refreshes mine a special command that prints stuff out.
你会看到它刷新了我的一个特殊指令，打印这些东西
trashing your terminal is basically deleting whatever's running in it,
终止你的终端基本上就是删除其中运行的所有东西
and the x is just hiding it.
而X键只是暂时隐藏它
And as hitting Ctrl tilde or toggling our terminal or whatever command it is on your environment,
无论是使用 "Ctrl + ~" 还是切换我们的终端，或是你环境中的任何此类命令
that's equivalent to hitting the hide, not the trash.
它都相当于点击隐藏而不是终止
So if we want to remove and start a terminal over,
所以，如果我们想删除并重新启动一个终端
we hit the trashcan, and then we pull it back up.
我们需要点击终止，然后再把它打开
Alright, so now we're gonna start working with ethers.
好了，现在我们就要开始使用 ethers
And we're going to start learning to code, our transactions and our contract deployments
我们将开始学习代码，交易，合约部署
and everything programmatically at a relatively low level.
以及一切以编程形式存在的相对底层的东西
And we're gonna learn how to deploy and interact with the contracts using the ethers JS package.
我们将学习如何使用 ethers.js 包部署合约并与之交互
Now to get started,
现在让我们开始吧
I'm going to recommend you create a folder
我建议你新建一个文件夹
where you're going to put all of your projects in it,
并把你所有的项目都放到这个文件夹里
I'm going to create a new directory called H H. hyphen, FCC,
我现在就新建一个文件夹名字叫 "hh-fcc"
which stands for hard hat Free Code Camp.
表示 "Hardhat Free Code Camp"
And once we run that command, we can cd into hh FCC.
运行完这个命令，我们就可以使用 "cd" 进入 "hh-fcc"
And this is where we'll create all of our projects for this course moving forward, so that we have them all in one place.
这里就是我们这门课程用来创建所有项目的地方，它们全部放在这一个地方
Now to get started, whenever you create a new project,
现在开始，每当你创建一个新项目时
you always want to create a new folder.
你都要想着创建一个新文件夹
So to create a new folder, we're going to do MK dir,
要想新建一个文件夹，我们输入 "mkdir"
and we're going to call this ethers, simple storage, like that.
并把它叫做 "ethers-simple-storage" 就像这样
And now, if you type ls, you'll see that there is one folder named ethers, simple storage.
现在，如果你输入 "ls"，你就会看到一个文件夹，名字是 "ethers-simple-storage"
ls is how you list all the contents of your folder.
"ls" 就是你用来显示文件夹内所有内容的方法
You might have a lot of other folders in here,
也许你这里还有很多其它文件夹
I only have the one since I created this new folder for this.
而我这只有一个，因为这是我新建一个的文件夹
Now what you can do, you can type code, ethers simple.
现在你能做的是，可以输入 "code ethers-simp"
And then if you hit tab, it should autocomplete for you.
这时如果你按下 "tab" 键，它应该会自动为你补全
And if you enter, Visual Studio code should open up
按下回车，Visual Studio Code 就会给你打开
a new Visual Studio code for you.
一个新的 Visual Studio Code
That is inside of either simple storage
它位于 "ethers-simple-storage" 里面
if you open up your terminal now,
如果你现在打开终端
your home directory for this workspace is going to be through simple storage as this is what pops up.
你所处的工作区目录就是 "ethers-simple-storage"  就和这里弹出来的这个一样
If that doesn't work for you, we can also do is you can hit File, Open folder
如果你的情况不是这样的，我们也可以通过点击 "文件-打开文件夹"
and then open the folder that you just created or that you want to open
并打开你刚刚创建的文件夹或是你想打开的其他文件夹
this again we'll open up VS code. And if we open up our terminal
这将再次打开 VS Code，并且如果我们打开终端
we see we're inside of ether simple storage.
能看到我们就在 "ethers-simple=storage" 里面
This is so powerful because as we create files
这一点非常强大，因为当我们创建文件时
we'll be able to See those files in our Explorer here,
我们能在这里的资源管理器中直接看到它们
this button here stands for the Explorer.
这个按钮表示资源管理器
If we click it, we can see the different files in here.
如果我们点击它，可以在这里查看不同的文件
And I'm going to go ahead and actually delete this file dot txt, because we're not actually going to use that.
我要把这个 "file.txt" 删除掉，因为我们其实并不会用到它
Now it's this part of the course, where we're actually going to start jumping into some JavaScript.
现在开始的这部分课程，我们要讲一些 JavaScript 的知识
Since this course is in JavaScript course,
因为本课程是一门基于 JavaScript 的课程
if you're unfamiliar with JavaScript,
如果你不太熟悉 JavaScript
it might be a little bit tricky.
可能会感到有些棘手
If you want to come into this with a better understanding of JavaScript and Node js,
如果你想进一步更好地理解 JavaScript 和 Node.js
there is a Free Code Camp YouTube video teaching No, Jas for beginners.
这里有一个 Free Code Camp 的 YouTube 视频，为初学者教授 Node.js
And a link to this will be in the GitHub repo associated with this course.
链接就在课程关联的 GitHub 仓库内
There's also a JavaScript  video
同样还有一个 Free Code Camp 的 JavaScript 视频
that I'm also going to put in the description for this course,
我会把它也一并放到本课程的描述中去
keep in mind that JavaScript and Node js are slightly different.
请记住 JavaScript 和 Node.js 还是有一些不同的
And we are going to go over some of the differences as we code along here.
我们在写代码的时候会讲到这些不同之处
But for the most part,
但在绝大多数情况下
learning one means you've learned the majority of the other.
学会其中一个就意味着你也学会了另一个的绝大部分
So if you want to pause and go through these videos, before continuing here,
所以你要是打算现在暂停下来，并在继续之前先去看一下这些视频的话
please feel free to do so
请按照你的需求自行决定吧
you don't have to, you can absolutely continue on with the course as is.
这也不是必须的，你完全可以接着继续本课程的学习
And if you get confused or stuck on some JavaScript piece,
如果你对某些 JavaScript 的内容感到困惑
feel free to pause, Google it and come back.
随时暂停，Google 一下然后再回来
But just to reiterate, you can check out the JavaScript programming full course.
不过重申一下，你可以先查看 JavaScript 编程的完整课程
And also the Node js full course, as those are both going to help you.
当然还有 Node.js 的完整课程，因为它们都能对你有所帮助
Like I was saying before, Node js is a JavaScript runtime.
正如我之前所说的，Node.js 是 JavaScript 运行的
So it's not exactly JavaScript.
所以它并不完全是 JavaScript
But we're going to write our code in JavaScript.
但我们要用 JavaScript 来编写代码
And if that's confusing, just don't worry about it right now.
如果这让你感到困惑，请暂时不要担心这个
And as we go through this course, I'll show you where the differences are.
当我们完成这门课时，我会告诉你它们的区别在哪
But basically, you can think of no Jas and JavaScript kind of being the same thing.
但基本上来说，你可以认为 Node.js 和 JavaScript 就是同样的东西
The big thing about Node js is it allows us to write JavaScript code in the back end,
Node.js 最重要的一点是它允许我们在后端编写 JavaScript 代码
as opposed to running JavaScript on the front end,
而不是在前端运行 JavaScript
JavaScript is made to be a browser run language,
JavaScript 是一种运行在浏览器上的语言
like running inside of, you know, Chrome, brave Firefox, etc.
比如说运行于 Chrome，Brave，Firefox 等等
No, Jas allows it to become a a scripting language, a back end language,
Node.js 允许它成为一种脚本语言，后端语言
which is why the syntax between the front end JavaScript and the back end JavaScript
这就是为什么前端 JavaScript 和后端 JavaScript
or the no JS JavaScript are going to be a little bit different.
或 Node.js JavaScript 的语法之间会有一些不同
Additionally, as we go along in this code,
此外，当我们编写代码的时候
if you're familiar with TypeScript,
如果你更熟悉 TypeScript 的话
all of our code is going to come with a TypeScript edition.
所有的代码都附带了一个 TypeScript 版本
TypeScript is what's known as a statically typed version of JavaScript.
TypeScript 就是所谓的 JavaScript 的静态类型版本
And it'll be it'll be this one. It'll be TypeScript, not TypeScript edition.
是 typescript 这个，而不是 typescript-edition 这个
I'll go ahead and fix that and remove this one to make it clear.
我会修改一下，把这个去掉，让它更清晰一些
TypeScript is a type safe version of JavaScript,
TypeScript 是 JavaScript 的一种安全版本
which is that's confusing, don't worry too much about that.
如果你暂时搞不明白，也不要太担心
But we are going to do all of our programming in JavaScript.
我们在编程过程中使用的是 JavaScript
And then if the code is different enough,
但如果代码的差异足够大
I'll show you how to do it in TypeScript as well.
我也会展示一下 TypeScript 应该怎么做
However, for most of them, we're not going to show you the TypeScript editions,
然而，它们其中的大多数，我们都不会展示 TypeScript 版本的过程
because it's going to be really similar.
因为它们实在是太相似了
But you can always refer back to the GitHub repository to see all the code for the TypeScript.
但你可以随时参考 GitHub 仓库以查看完整的 TypeScript 代码
Now, if you're new to this space,
如果你是这个领域的新手
I actually do recommend you go ahead and start with JavaScript
那我真的非常建议你从 JavaScript 开始学起
and learn how to do TypeScript later on.
并在那之后学习如何使用 TypeScript
TypeScript actually catches bugs early on,
TypeScript 可以让你更早地捕捉到 bug
making it a lot easier to code your projects in the long run.
从长远来看，这使得项目代码的编写变得更加容易
However, it does take a lot of extra typing.
然而，它确实需要大量额外的输入
And it can be a little bit frustrating learning how types work for beginners,
并且对初学者来说，学习 Type 如何运作的过程可能是令人沮丧的
JavaScript is a little bit more loose as a language
JavaScript 作为一种语言比较宽松，我们可以做任何想做的事
and lets us kind of do whatever we want, but it can cause a headache later on.
但之后会让人头疼
So if you do run into some issues, and you do run into some bugs,
所以如果你确实遇到了一些问题，确实遇到了一些 bug
it might be a good idea to try TypeScript on for size, and see how that fares.
那么尝试一下 TypeScript 可能是一个好主意，看看结果如何
Well. Let's go ahead and begin working on our local development environment
好了，让我们开始在我们的本地开发环境中工作
and getting set up to do everything in ethers Jas and in JavaScript.
并准备好在 ethers.js 和 JavaScript 中要做的所有事
Oops. And I actually went and renamed this folder to ether symbol storage dash, FCC.
哦，其实我把这个文件夹重命名成了 "ethers-simple-storage-fcc"
Reason I added this dash FCC
之所以我添加了这个 "-fcc"
is all the GitHub repositories associated with this course,
是因为与本课程关联的所有 Github 仓库
all the GitHub repos that have this dash FCC
这些 GitHub 仓库都有这个 "-fcc"
to know that it is part of this hard hat JavaScript course.
这是为了让大家知道这是 JavaScript Hardhat 课程的一部分
Awesome. Let's jump in. Let's start working with solidity and our smart contracts
太棒了，让我们出发吧，让我们开始在我们的智能合约中使用 solidity
locally in Visual Studio code,
并且是在本地的 Visual Studio Code 中
as you can probably tell by the name of this folder.
可能从这个文件夹的名字就可以看出来
And of course, if you looked at the code,
如果你来查看代码
this project is going to be our simple storage project,
就会发现这个项目就是我们的 "simple storage" 项目
but developed locally using ethers.
但这次是在本地的 ethers 上开发的
So the first thing that we want to do is want to get in that smart contract code.
所以我们要做的第一件事就是进入智能合约的代码
So what we can do is make sure we have the Explorer selected,
我们要做的就是选中资源管理器
we can go ahead and right click and select new file
继续右键单击并选择 "新建文件(New File)"
and do simple storage. So just close this for now.
并输入 "SimpleStorage.sol"，暂时先关闭这个
And we can copy paste our simple storage code from our last section into VS code.
然后我们可以把上节课的 simple storage 代码复制到 VS Code 中
If you closed remix or you forgot where it is,
如果你已经把 Remix 关了或是忘记把代码放到哪里了
you can just go to the ethers simple storage FCC repo,
那你可以去 "ethers-simple-storage-fcc" 仓库
it's simple storage dot Sol, and we can just copy all the code in here
找到 "SimpleStorage.sol" 并复制这里的所有代码
and then come back over select Symbol storage that Saul and paste it in.
然后返回这里，选中 "SimpleStorage.sol" 粘贴进去
Now an important note about Visual Studio code
现在要讲一个关于 Visual Studio Code 的重要说明
is that when you see this little white.up here,
就是当你在这里看到一个小白点时
it means that this file isn't saved
它的意思是这个文件还没有被保存
to save your Git file. To save, and it'll go away like that.
要想保存的话你可以点击 "文件(File)-保存(Save)"，然后它就会消失不见了
Or what you can do is you can hit command S or Ctrl S, depending on if you're on a Windows, Mac, or Linux.
或者你可以按 "Command + S" 或 "Ctrl + S"，取决于你用的是 Windows，Mac 或者 Linux
Now you'll see here that this code is a little bit hard to read the simple storage dot salt,
正如你所见的，这个代码有些不便阅读，就是这个 "SimpleStorage.sol"
it doesn't have the syntax highlighting that we saw in remix.
它并没有我们在 Remix 里见到过的那种语法高亮
So we want to go ahead and add a Visual Studio Code extension
所以我们现在要添加 Visual Studio Code 的扩展(Extension)
to give this syntax highlighting.
以提供语法高亮功能
So what we can do
我们该怎么做呢
is come over to this bar over here looks like this.
到这里的这一栏来，就是这一个
And if you don't see it on the left hand bar,
如果你在左侧栏里没有看到它
you should click these three dots, and it should be in here.
那你需要点击这三个小点，它应该就在这里
But we'll go ahead and click Extensions. And what we're going to do is we're going to look up, solidity plus hard hat.
继续点击扩展，我们要做的就是向上看，输入 "solidity + hardhat"
And we're going to install this solidity plus hard hat extension. For VS code.
然后为 VS Code 安装这个 "solidity + hardhat" 扩展
Now that we have this installed,
现在我们已经安装好了
if we go back over to our simple storage dot sole,
如果我们回到我们的 "SimpleStorage.sol"
you'll see that all the highlighting is back in.
你就会看到所有高亮都已经出现了
And now it's much easier to read.
现在明显更容易阅读了
Right? So this is good. We have our code in here we have our syntax highlighting.
很好，我们已经有了代码，还有了语法高亮
Now let's add an auto format or or default format or
现在让我们添加一个自动格式化或者说默认格式化的程序
right now our code is pretty good with the way that it's formatted.
现在我们的代码的格式化程度已经很不错了
But what if we, we accidentally do some stuff like this or like this,
但如果我们，我们不小心做了一些类似这样或这样的事
or maybe even like this, we add a ton of new lines, etc,
甚至可能是这样，我们添加了成吨的空行，等等
our code can start to look pretty gross.
我们的代码现在看起来很恶心
And even though the code itself is fine,
即使这个代码本身并没有什么问题
and it'll run the exact same way, with all this extra whitespace,
它也确实会按照正确的方式运行哪怕是有这些额外的空白区域
it doesn't look very good, right.
但它看起来就是不太好，对吧
And due to that, it can be a little bit hard to read. What we want to do, then, we want to open up our settings and adjust our vias code so that it auto formats whenever we
save, so whenever we save, so that whenever it goes from the
little white dot here to no white dot, this whole thing gets
automatically formatted to some looks really nice. Okay. So what
we can do is we can open up our command palette to open up our
command palette, you can hit View command palette, and we'll
get a little pop up that looks like this. Another way to open
up your command palette is you're gonna hit Command, Shift
P, or Ctrl, Shift P, depending on your Mac, or Linux or
Windows. And what we want to do is we want to type in settings,
and we're going to open Settings JSON, we don't want to open the
default settings JSON. We don't want to touch these. But we want
to open our JSON settings. You'll also notice there are
user settings and workspace settings. These are pieces that
we can adjust as well. But we're going to just go right into the
JSON settings. So So I already have some stuff in here, but
yours might be blank. Or you might have some stuff in here as
well. So what we're going to do is if you have stuff in here
already, we're going to add a comma, then we're going to do
quotes, solidity. Close the brackets, we're gonna do a
little colon and something like this. This means that we're
going to apply some settings to our Visual Studio Code. Whenever
we're working with solidity, one of the things we're going to add
in here is going to be an editor, Doc's default, for
matter. And you might even get a pop up that tells you some
different things that we can use for a default format or our
default format, or is going to be Nanak, foundation, dot hard
hat, hyphens solidity. This will mean that any time we go to
format our code, it'll use the hard hat solidity plug in, as
its default format, or the hard hat solidity plugin comes with
some formatting, and a lot of other really useful tools for us
writing our code. So now that we have this part in, the next
thing we're going to do is add format on Save. If we haven't
already, we could add it in here in our JSON, but I'm going to
add it not in the JSON file, I'm going to add it in the overall
file. So if we open that command palette back up, and we type in
settings, open user settings, this is another really good
place where we can look in add settings with the UI. So these
two do essentially the same thing. It's just that this one
has dials and a little bit more context versus settings that
JSON just says Okay, give me the raw code for it. This tells us a
little bit more. So you can use either one. But we're going to
look for format, on save. And you're going to want this
checked if you haven't already. This means that every time we
save VS code is going to try to format our code for us. So now
that we have this checked, we have settings dot JSON added in.
And remember, we want to save this. Remember, if you see this
white dot, that means not saved. So you're gonna want to save it
and close it out. Let me close this out too. If we come back in
here and we add a bunch of random new spaces or whatever,
you want to make it look a little bit ugly, and then we
save it. It should automatically reformat to look much nicer,
right. So if we do something like this, we'd save it
reformats it to look much nicer this one make them more readable
for you, and more readable for anybody else who looks at your
code. And it's just really nice. And this line of code for your
settings dot JSON is located in the full blockchain study
course.js. So you can also just copy paste it, we are going to
end up overriding that default format or with another format
are called prettier pretty soon. But it's great to have a default
format or so that if you don't feel like adding the prettier
code sometime in the future, you can just rely on your default
formatter. Awesome. While we're doing formatting, let's also add
a default format or for our JavaScript code. And just to
test it out, let's go ahead and create our new file, we'll call
it deploy dot Jas. And in here, we can do something like
function Hi,
console dot log, hi, and then just add and then just make it
look kind of gross, maybe something like this. If you hit
save, and it does some auto formatting, that's great, you
can actually turn that off by going back to your command
palette, and saying, Save without formatting. And that way
it will be saved and not formatted. The way we can add
some other formatting here is we're gonna install another
extension, this one is going to be called prettier. So we can
just look up prettier and extensions here. And you'll want
to install this prettier code formatter. So we're gonna go
ahead and install this. And great, now it's installed
prettier is a form is a code format, or that works for many
languages like Python, JavaScript, and even solidity.
And pretty soon we're going to use prettier for both JavaScript
and solidity. But for now, we're just going to use prettier for
JavaScript, we can enable this by opening back up our command
palette, we'll go to preferences, open Settings. And
the same way we added a solidity section, we're going to add a
JavaScript section. So we're going to add a comma here, some
quotes, brackets, we're going to type in JavaScript, close that
colon brackets. And we're going to do the same thing at the door
dot default, or matter. Net we're going to do and then in
here, we're going to do e s BENP, that prettier, hyphen VS
code. And this will make prettier the default editor for
JavaScript. Now, like I said, pretty soon, we're going to have
prettier override both of these for solidity and JavaScript. And
we're going to give prettier some parameters so that no
matter who uses your code, they will always have the exact same
formatting. But now that we have prettier in here as the default
editor, if we come back to deploy dot j s, and we hit save,
it should format to look a little something like this. Now,
we go ahead and we do something like this. If we go ahead and do
something like this, it'll reformat to look like look like
that. And then additionally, if you want to go back to the
command palette, open user settings, not in JSON mode, and
we go to default format, or you can actually even select the
default format or for all languages, if you want to use
prettier for all formatters. Feel free to go ahead. Alright,
great, got our JavaScript format, or in as well, let's
start writing some JavaScript code.